American Philosophical Society Archives. Record Group IIb. 1807-1825 APS.Archives.IIb APS.Archives.IIb
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - John Spear Smith to John Vaughan, March 3, 1818; 8" x 10"; Smith, John Spear, d. 1866
    Baltimore, 1p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Inquires concerning a case of books sent to John Vaughan by Mr. Michaux.
  - Letter to [John] Vaughan, March 13, 1818; 10x8; Joseph Bonaparte, King of Spain, 1768-1844
    Point Breeze, A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. Could not meet with the APS.
  - Edw(ard) Earle to the A.P.S., March 14, 1818; 8 1/4" x 9 7/8"; Earle, Edward, 1760?-1847?
    ----, 1p. A.L.S. Wishes to be appointed publisher of Chief Justice Tilghman's Eulogium on Dr. Wistar.
  - Report of committee on Dr. Drake's geological memoir, March 19, 1818; 10x8; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: Zaccheus Collins and Thos.Nuttall. 1p.and end. Cf. Minutes, P.480.
  - Copy of application from committee of A.P.S. to the U. S. government for astronomical instruments, April 3, 1818; 7 1/2" x 9"; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, 3 pp. and endorsement. Dr.D.S.: R[obert] Patterson and four others.
  - John Vaughan to John Sergeant and Jos[eph] Hopkinson, April 4, 1818; 8 1/4" x 7 3/8"; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. L. Handwriting of John Vaughan. Encloses application for astronomical instruments for Centre Square observatory.
  - Letter to Thomas Parke, V.P. of the College of Physicians, April 6, 1818; 8 1/4" x 9 3/4"; American Philosophical Society
    Phila., A.L.S.: Jn. Vaughan, Libn. 1p. and add. Use of the Society's hall for meetings of various institutions. Printed:APS Library Bulletin for 1950,p.202. Lingelbach. The Story of Philosophical Hall.
  - Peter S. DuPonceau to John Vaughan, April 6, 1818; 5 1/8" x 8 3/8"; Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
    [Philadelphia], 1 p. and address. A.L.S. May obtain some documents relating to the Paxton boys from Samuel Fisher; has received more documents from Rev. [John] Heckewelder.
  - John Sergeant to John Vaughan, April 6, 1818; 7 7/8" x 9 5/8"; Sergeant, John, 1747-1824
    Washington, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Acknowledges receipt of request for astronomical instruments. Will do what he can to obtain them.
  - John Sergeant to John Vaughan, April 7, 1818; 7 7/8" x 9 1/2"; Sergeant, John, 1747-1824
    Washington, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Has presented application of A.P.S. for astronomical instruments to the Secretary of the Treasury.
  - Letter to [Joseph Bonaparte] Comte de Survilliers, April 8, 1818; 8-1/2x10; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. Forwards Transactions, n.s.,v.I.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, April 9, 1818; 8" x 9 3/4"; Hosack, David, 1769-1835
    New York, A.L.S. 3p. and add., end. Lists persons desiring APS Transactions; commends appearance of last volume. Mentions Judge Cooper.
  - Letter to [Thomas Jefferson], April 12, 1818; 12-1/2x7-1/2; Steel, Hugh
    Belleville, Ill., A.L.S. 4p., end. (see Ms.Comm.to APS. Natural history, vol. 2, no.60.) Concerning the western territory. Enc. originally in letter from Steel to T.Jefferson; April 12, 1818.
  - Letter to Thomas Jefferson, April 14, 1818; Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
    Philadelphia, L. 1p. (see APS. Historical...committee. Letterbooks, vol. 2, p. 11.) Concerning the Lewis and Clark journals. Film 199 Frame 138
  - Receipt for fossil remains, bones, etc. received from administrators of estate of Caspar Wistar, April 15, 1818; 10x7-1/2; American Philosophical Society
    Phila., D.S.: Jno. Vaughan 1p., end. Copy Endorsed: The original in hand writing of Dr Horner & with a receipt similar to this was sent to James Gibson.
  - Report of committee on renting room in the Hall, April 17, 1818; 7x8; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: R.Patterson and R.M. Patterson. 1p.and end. Cf. Minutes, p.481.
  - John Quincy Adams to John Vaughan, April 23, 1818; 7 15/16" x 9 13/16"; Adams, John Quincy, 1767-1848
    Washington, 1 p. and endorsements. Acknowledges his election to membership in the American Philosophical Society.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, April 24, 1818; 10x8; Joseph Bonaparte, King of Spain, 1768-1844
    Point Breeze, L.S. 1p.,end.and add. In French. Thanks for publication.
  - John Quincy Adams to J. E. Hall, April 27, 1818; 7 7/8" x 9 3/4"; Adams, John Quincy, 1767-1848
    Washington, 1 p. Returns thanks to Mr. Hall for proposing him for membership in the American Philosophical Society.
  - Jacob Bigelow to John Vaughan, April 27, 1818; 7 7/8" x 9 5/8"; Bigelow, Jacob, 1786-1879
    Boston, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Acknowledges election to membership in the American Philosophical Society.
  - Will[iam] Gaston to R[obert] M. Patterson, April 27, 1818; 7 7/8" x 9 3/4"; Gaston, William, 1778-1844
    Secretary of the A.P.S., Newbern, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Acknowledges his election to membership in the American Philosophical Society.
  - P. Pedersen to John Vaughan, April 27, 1818; 7 5/8" x 9 3/8"; Pedersen, Peder, 1774-1851
    [Philadelphia], 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Presents to the A.P.S.: a map of the island of Sealand, published under the direction of the Royal Danish Society of Sciences.
  - P. Pedersen to John Vaughan, April 27, 1818; 7 3/4" x 9 7/8"; Pedersen, Peder, 1774-1851
    Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsements. A.L.S. Acknowledges the receipt of A.P.S. Transactions, n.s., I. Shall forward a copy to the Royal Danish Society of Sciences.
  - Josiah Meigs to John Vaughan, April 28, 1818; 7 7/8" x 9 5/8"; Meigs, Josiah, 1757-1822
    Librarian of the A.P.S., Washington, 2 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Returns thanks for his election to membership in "the most distinguished Literary Society in the Western Continent... "
  - Report of committee on the library, April 30, 1818; 5 1/4" x 8 3/8"; American Philosophical Society
    [to the American Philosophical Society], appointed to consider M. Cassin's communication on the subject of the Paris agency, [Philadelphia], April 30, 1818. 1 p. and endorsement. A.D.S.: G[eorge] Ord. Recommend agency of M. Bertrand of Paris.
  - Letter to [John] Vaughan, May 4, 1818; 8x5; Pedersen, Peder, 1774-1851
    A.L.S. 1p. Forwards publication.
  - Tho[mas] B. Wait to John Vaughan, May 7, 1818; 7 15/16" x 9 13/16"; Wait, Thomas Baker, 1762-1830
    Boston, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Offers to present to the A.P.S. the State Papers of Washington's and Adams's administrations, and to add the Confidential State Papers, "up to the close of the late war."
  - Parker Cleaveland to John Vaughan, May 10, 1818; 7 1/16" x 9 3/8"; Cleaveland, Parker, 1780-1858
    Librarian of the A.P.S., Brunswick, Me., 2 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Acknowledges his election to membership in the American Philosophical Society.
  - Josiah Meigs to R[obert] M. Patterson, May 12, 1818; 7 13/16" x 9 9/16"; Meigs, Josiah, 1757-1822
    Washington, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Acknowledges his election to membership in the American Philosophical Society.
  - John Sergeant to John Vaughan, May 12, 1818; 8" x 9 7/8"; Sergeant, John, 1747-1824
    Washington, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Col. Lane will forward to the A.P.S. two specimens of the marble used in the columns of the House of Representatives.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, secretary of APS, May 14, 1818; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Library Company of Philadelphia
    Philadelphia, Printed L.S: Benjn. R. Morgan, secretary. 1p. and end. Acknowledges Vol.1,n.s. of APS Transactions.
  - John Quincy Adams to R[obert] M. Patterson,Secretary of the A.P.S., May 18, 1818; 7 7/8" x 9 3/4"; Adams, John Quincy, 1767-1848
    Washington, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Acknowledges receipt of certificate of membership in the American Philosophical Society.
  - John Quincy Adams to John Vaughan, May 18, 1818; 7 7/8" x 9 11/16"; Adams, John Quincy, 1767-1848
    Washington, 1 p. and endorsements. A.L.S. Encloses $10, in payment of admission fee to the A.P.S.
  - Nath[aniel] Bowditch to John Vaughan, May 19, 1818; 7 7/8" x 10"; Bowditch, Nathaniel, 1773-1838
    Salem, [Mass.], 1 p., address and endorsement. A.N. in 3d.per. Presents a pamphlet of his to the A.P.S. library.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, May 21, 1818; Athenaeum of Philadelphia
    Philadelphia, Printed L.S: Robert H. Smith, secretary. 1p. and end. Acknowledges volume of APS Transactions.
  - Jacob Bigelow to R[obert] M. Patterson, May 24, 1818; 7 7/8" x 9 11/16"; Bigelow, Jacob, 1786-1879
    Secretary of the A.P.S., Boston, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Acknowledges receipt of diploma of membership in the American Philosophical Society.
  - James Jackson to R[obert] M. Patterson, May 28, 1818; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Jackson, James
    Secretary of the A.P.S., Boston, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Acknowledges receipt of certificate of membership in the A.P.S. Enclosed in: James Jackson to John Vaughan, May 28, 1818.
  - J[ames] Jackson to John Vaughan, May 28, 1818; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Jackson, James
    Boston, 2 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Concerning his election to membership in the A.P.S. Letter to the secretary enclosed.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, May 30, 1818; 7 3/4" x 12 3/4"; Tilghman, William, 1756-1827
    Lancaster, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Encloses a print of the Paxtang riot, sent by Charles Smith for the Committee [Historical and literary committee?].
  - Letter to John Vaughan, June 2, 1818; 10x8 12-1/2x7-1/2; Currie, William, 1754-1828
    A.L.S. 12p.and add., end. Enc. (see Ms.comm.to the APS. Natural philosophy, vol. 2, no. 65.) Forwards memoir on criticisms of Newton to be read to the APS. Cf. Minutes, p.482.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, June 2, 1818; 9-1/2x8; Meigs, Josiah, 1757-1822
    Washington, A.L.S. 2p.,add.and end. Concerning the command of his brother, Col. R.J. Meigs, among the Cherokees. Will furnish the APS with notices from the Land Office.
  - Tho[ma]s B. Wait to J[ohn] Vaughan, June 3, 1818; 7 15/16" x 9 13/16"; Wait, Thomas Baker, 1762-1830
    Boston, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Is sending to the A.P.S. four volumes of State Papers.
  - Geo[rge] Izard to John Vaughan, June 8, 1818; 5" x 7 3/4"; Izard, George, 1777-1828
    Librarian of A.P.S., [Philadelphia, 1p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Presents to the A.P.S.: Edmund Fry, Pantographia.
  - W[illia]m Graham to John Vaughan, June 17, 1818; 6 3/4" x 8"; Graham, William
    Chester, 2 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Will loan A.P.S. original of [William] Penn's delegation of his powers to the provincial council in 1684.
  - Letter to [the American Philosophical Society], June 18, 1818; 8-3/4x7-1/4; Macnab, Henry Gray, 1761-1823
    Paris, L.S. 3p. Forwards work on education and asks that any member write their ideas to him.
  - James Madison to (Peter S.) DuPonceau, June 18, 1818; 7 7/8" x 9 3/4"; Madison, James, 1749-1812
    Montpellier, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Approves purpose of Historical and Literary Committee of A.P.S. Thanks DuPonceau for copy of Phonology.
  - Note to [John Vaughan?], June 19, 1818; 8-1/2x6; Chapman, Nathaniel, 1780-1853
    A.N.S. 1p. and end. Concerning a paper by W. Currie to be read. See APS Minutes: APS Proc., vol.22, pt.3,482.
  - Letter to the Philosophical society, June 19, 1818; 8" x 10"; Geological Society of London
    London, A.L.S.: Henry Heuland, foreign secretary. 1p. and add., end. Acknowledges Vol.1,n.s. APS Transactions.
  - Jose(eph) P. Norris to Peter S. DuPonceau, June 19, 1818; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Norris, Joseph P. (Joseph Parker), 1763-1841
    Philadelphia, 1 p., address and endorsement. L.S. With regard to unnamed missing document.
  - Will(iam) Gaston to John Vaughan, June 26, 1818; 7 15/16" x 9 3/4"; Gaston, William, 1778-1844
    Newbern, 2 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Acknowledges election to membership in the A.P.S. Concerning treaty with the Tuscarora Indians, November 25, 1712.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, 1821 July 9; Vaughan, William, 1752-1850
    Note from William to John Vaughan, regarding copies of the Philosophical Transactions of the Royal Society No. 2 for 1820 and No. 1 for 1821, that he had transmitted to John as Librarian of the A.P.S.. He asked that John send an acknowledgment.
  - Letter to the president and council of the A.P.S, July 16, 1818; 8" x 10"; Linnean Society of London
    London, Printed form S: Alex. Macleay, secretary. 1p. and end. Acknowledges A.P.S. Transactions, n.s.v.1
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, July 17, 1818; 10x8; Tanner, Vallance, Kearny & Co.
    Library Street, L.S. 1P. and add., end. Encloses volume.
  - Letter to the Librarian of the A.P.S., July 22, 1818; 9x7-1/2; Society for the Encouragement of Arts, Manufactures, and Commerce (Great Britain)
    L.S.: Arthur Aikin. 1p. and end. Forwards publication.
  - C(aesar) A. Rodney to P(eter) S. DuPonceau, August 6, 1818; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Rodney, C. A. (Caesar Augustus), 1772-1824
    Wilmington, 2 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Presents silver medal commemorating Declaration of Independence of Chili to Historical and Literary Committee of the A.P.S.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Aug. 6, 1818; 8" x 9 3/4"; Todd, John Payne, 1792-1858
    Mont Pellier, A.L.S. 1p. Encloses a copy of address by Mr. Madison before the Agricultural society of Albemarle. Cf. Minutes of Aug. 21, 1818.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., Aug. 7, 1818; 10x8; Reale accademia delle scienze di Torino
    Turin, L.S.: Vassalli-Eandi. 2p. and end. In French. Forwards publications.
  - John Quincy Adams to John Vaughan, August 14, 1818; 7 7/8" x 9 3/4"; Adams, John Quincy, 1767-1848
    Washington, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Will "take care that the Society be duly supplied with sets of the Public Documents."
  - G[erhard] Troost to John Vaughan, August 14, 1818; 8" x 10 1/8"; Troost, Gerard, 1776-1850
    Baltimore, 1 p. A.L.S. Donates samples of amber found at Cape Sable to the A.P.S.
  - J[ohn] C. Calhoun to Jno. Vaughan, August 15, 1818; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Calhoun, John C. (John Caldwell), 1782-1850
    Librarian of the A.P.S., War Department, [Washington], 2 pp. and endorsement. L.S. Acknowledging the receipt of two military books, forwarded by the A.P.S. to the war department.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Aug. 17, 1818; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Cist, Jacob, 1782-1825
    Wilkesbarre, A.L.S. 3p.,and add.,end. Donates a medal of the period of George I, found on Jacob's Plains near Wilkesbarre, to the APS.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Aug. 27, 1818; 8" x 9 3/4"; Vaughan, William, 1752-1850
    London, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Forwards thanks of the Linnean society for A.P.S. Transactions and other journals.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the APS, Sept. 8, 1818; 9X7 10x7-3/4; McWilliam, Robert
    London, L.S. 2p.and end. Presents copy of his publication on dry-rot. (for publication,see: 634.9:M25).----Copy. 3p.,end. Enclosed originally in: Rush to APS; Sept.14,1818.
  - Letter to Robert Patterson, secretary of American society of sciences of Philadelphia, Sept. 12, 1818; 7 3/4" x 8 3/4"; Fuss, Nikolaĭ Ivanovich, 1755-1826
    St. Petersburg, A.L.S. 2p. and end. In French. Acknowledges election to membership in the Society.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Sept. 12, 1818; 9x8; Imperatorskai︠a︡ akademīi︠a︡ nauk i khudozhestv (Russia)
    St.Petersburg, L.S.: Nicolas Fuss. 2p. and end. In French. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to Levett Harris, Sept. 14, 1818; 8" x 10"; Fuss, Nikolaĭ Ivanovich, 1755-1826
    St. Petersburg, Extract of L. 2p. In French. Relative to the publications of the Academy at St. Petersburg which are to be sent to the Society at Philadelphia. Enclosed originally with letter from Harris to Vaughan. Dec. 29,1818.
  - Richard Rush to the Secretary of the American Philosophical Society, September 14, 1818; 8" x 10"; Rush, Richard, 1780-1859
    London, 2 pp. and endorsement. A.L.S. Transmits to the A.P.S.: an essay upon the dry rot in timber, by [Robert] McWilliam.
  - Roberts Vaux to the American Philosophical Society, September 17, 1818; 7 3/4" x 9 7/8"; Vaux, Roberts, 1786-1836
    Philadelphia, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Presents box made from wood of Penn treaty tree to A.P.S. See Minutes, September 18, 1818, in Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 483.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, 1818 September 25; Ramsay, James B.
    Letter accompanying a copy of a History of United States by David Ramsay presented by James Ramsay.
  - Letter to [John Vaughan], Sept. 29, 1818; 10x8; Quabeck, A. L. G., viscount de
    Philadelphia, A.L.in 3rd.P. 1p.and end. Will forwards APS publications to the Bataviaasche genootschap van kunsten en wetenschappen.
  - Report of committee on Cooper's paper on potash and yellow fever, Oct. 2, 1818; 9-1/2x8; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: William Hembel, jr. and R.M.Patterson 1p.and end. ----Copy. 1p. Cf. Minutes, p.483.
  - Isaiah Thomas to John Vaughan, October 6, 1818; 8" x 10"; Thomas, Isaiah, 1749-1831
    Treasurer of the A.P.S., Worcester, Mass., 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Offers for the acceptance of the A.P.S. "a file of Newspapers for the Thirty years last past, bound in 14 volumes."
  - Report of committee on Nulty's paper on pendulums, Oct. 16, 1818; 8x8; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: R.M.Patterson. 1p.and end, Cf.-Minutes, p.483. Printed: APS Transactions, n.s., II, 466 ff.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Oct. 16, 1818; 10x8; Greuhm,
    A.L.S. 1p.and end. Has forwarded publication to the Berlin academy of sciences.
  - Letter to Levett Harris, Oct. 29, 1818; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Adelung, Friedrich von, 1768-1843
    St. Petersburg, Extract of a L. 1p. In French. Relative to the receipt of Memoirs of the Russian academy from Mr. de Fuss for the Philosophical Society.
  - Letter to Peter [S.] DuPonceau, Philadelphia, Oct. 29, 1818; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Butrick, D. S. (Daniel Sabin), 1789-1847
    Brainerd, A.L.S. 2p.and add.,end. Enc. Encloses a verb conjugation in the Cherokee language. Concerning his hopes for making a Cherokee grammar. For enclosure, see: Butrick. Conjugation...;[Oct. 29,1818]. (see Vocabularies...Indian languages, no. 41.)
  - Letter to the Consul of the U.S. at Leghorn, Nov. 3, 1818; 10x8-1/2; Università di Pisa
    Pisa, L.S.: Benjamin Sproni. Copy. 2p. In French. Forwards books to the APS.
  - Letter to the secretary of the A.P.S, Nov. 6, 1818; 8" x 10 1/2"; Society for the Encouragement of Arts, Manufactures, and Commerce (Great Britain)
    London, Printed from filled in in ms.S: Ar[thur] Aikin, secretary. 1p. and add.end. Acknowledges vol.1, n.s. of A.P.S. Transactions.
  - John C. Warren to John Vaughan, November 16, 1818; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Warren, John Collins, 1778-1856
    Boston, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Acknowledges his election to membership in the American Philosophical Society.
  - Letter to the secretary of the A.P.S, Dec. 12, 1818; 7 1/2" x 9 1/2"; Literary and Philosophical Society of Manchester
    Manchester, A.L.S: William Henry, V[ice] P[resident] 1p. and add.,and. Acknowledges Vol.1, n.s. of the A.P.S. Transactions. Manchester Society will soon offer a new volume of their Memoirs in return Cf. Minutes of April 16, 1819.
  - Josiah Quincy to [John Vaughan], December 15, 1818; 7 3/4" x 9 9/16"; Quincy, Josiah
    Boston, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Presents to the A.P.S.: Memoirs of the American Academy of Arts and Sciences, IV, pt. 1.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Dec. 29, 1818; 7 3/4" x 10"; Harris, Levett
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. and end. Memoirs of the Imperial academy of sciences of St. Petersburg for the A.P.S. Encloses extract of letter from Prof. Fuss relative to same. (For enclosure, see letter from Fuss to Harris; Sept.14, 1818)
  - Receipt to John Vaughan for purchase of books, Dec. 30, 1818; 10x6-1/2; Kuhn, G.
    Philadelphia, D.S. 1p.
  - L. Munsell to ----, December 30, 1818; 8" x 9 7/8"; Munsell, Luke
    [Philadelphia], 1p. and endorsement. Sends "one of my Maps of the State of Kentucky" to the A.P.S. See Minutes, January 15, 1819, in Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 484.
  - Letter to W[illia]m Vaughan, [1818]; 8" x 10"; London Institution
    [ca.] A.L.S: Wm. Maltby, principal librarian. 1p. and end. Acknowledges Vol. 1 of new series of APS Transactions.
  - List of books presented to the American Philosophical society..., 1818; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Adelung, Friedrich von, 1768-1843
    D. 1p. and end. (In hand of P.S. Du Ponceau)
  - Bataviasche genootschap van kunsten en wetenschappen. List of members, 1818; Bataviasche genootschap van kunsten en wetenschappen.
    Printed membership list.
  - John Sergeant to Robert M.(?) Patterson, January 6, 1819; 7 7/8" x 9 5/8"; Sergeant, John, 1747-1824
    Washington, 2 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Requests duplicate of memorial relative to mathematical instruments to present to the Secretary of War.
  - Josiah Quincy to John Vaughan, January 9, 1819; 7 3/4" x 9 9/16"; Quincy, Josiah
    Boston, 1 p. A.L.S. Encloses title page for Memoirs of American Academy of Arts and Sciences, IV, pt. 1.
  - Letter to Robert Patterson, Philadelphia, Jan. 12, 1819; 10x8; Nelson, Hugh, 1768-1836
    Washington, A.L.S. 2p.and add. (see Ms.comm.to the APS. Math.and astronomy, vol. 2, no. 96.) Concerning Lambert's calculation of the longitude of Washington.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Jan. 20, 1819; 8x5-1/2; Högelmüller, Georg, ritter von
    Vienna, L.S. 1p.and end. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to the President of the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Jan. 20, 1819; 11-1/2x7-1/2; Netherlands. Ministerie van Binnenlandse Zaken en Landbouw
    Brussels, L.S.: A.R.Faleg. 1p.,end. In French. Thanks for publication.
  - A.P.S. [Donations to the Library], January, 1819-February, 1820; American Philosophical Society.
    List of donations to the A.P.S. Library.
  - Letter to the A.P.S., Feb. 10, 1819; 9x7; Reale Istituto lombardo di scienze e lettere
    Milan, L.S.: Carlini. 1p. and add end. In Italian. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to the A.P.S., Feb.10, 1819; 13-1/2x9; Reale Istituto lombardo di scienze e lettere
    Milan, L.S.: Carlini. 2p. and end. In Italian. Forwards publication.
  - Letter to R.M. Patterson, Philadelphia, Feb. 12, 1819; 10x8; Asiatic Society of Bengal
    Calcutta, L.S.: H. H. Wilson. 1p. and add., end. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to J[ohn] Vaughan, Philadelphia, Feb. 12, 1819; 10x8; Asiatic Society of Bengal
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Feb. 15, 1819; 8x5; Walsh, Robert, 1784-1859
    A.L.S. 1p. and add.,end. Forwards publications and wishes to borrow books.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Philadelphia, Feb. 22, 1819; 10x8; Breislak, Scipion, 1748-1826
    A.L.S. 3p. and add., end. In French. Friendly letter. Forwards publications. Geology. Mentions T.Jefferson, Maclure and Lesueur. Contains also prospectus of Breislak's books. FILM199 FRAME 420
  - A. Richards to Sam(ue)l L. Mitchell, February 23, 1819; 8" x 10"; Richards, A.
    New York, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Will find conveyance for package sent from Mexico to the A.P.S. and College of Physicians.
  - Sam(ue)l L. Mitchell to P(eter) S. DuPonceau, February 24, 1819; 4 3/4" x 7 3/4"; Mitchill, Samuel L. (Samuel Latham), 1764-1831
    New York, 4 pp. A.L.S. Thanks DuPonceau for his report on the languages of the American Indians. Remarks upon characteristics of American aborigines.
  - Letter to [Robert Patterson] the president of the APS, Feb. 28, 1819; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Symmes, John Cleves, 1780-1829
    Cincinnati, A.L.S. 2p.and end. Is sending communication on concentric spheres to the APS. For Communication, see: Symmes. On light between the sphers. (Printed catalogue)
  - Letter to the A.P.S., Feb., 1819; 10x8; Schröder, Johan Henrik, 1791-1857
    Upsala, A.L.S. 1p. and end. In Latin. Forwards publications.